# **Steven Quintana**

# Full Stack Software Engineer

steve.e.quint@gmail.com | (858) 775-3034 | 25 Ceramica, Rancho Santa Margarita, CA, 92688

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/sequint">https://github.com/sequint</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://sequint.github.io/portfolio-site">https://sequint.github.io/portfolio-site</a> | LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/steven-quintana-278b0091/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/steven-quintana-278b0091/</a>

# **SUMMARY**

Passionate and driven Full Stack Engineer recently graduated from UC Irvine's Full Stack Software Development Bootcamp. Experience building strong and user friendly applications utilizing modern technologies such as React, Node, Express, and MongoDB. Recently completed a full Mern stack applications geared for commercial use in HR departments, leading a team of six developers over a two week period with daily sprint activities culminating in the final project.

Certifications also include ES6 Javascript and C++ Programming. Was a top performer and leader in all classes, taking on the role of team lead, mentor, and full stack developer.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Front End: React.js, Javascript, Material UI, Multiple modern styling frameworks, HTML/CSS

Back End: Node.js, Express.js, NPM, C++, MongoDB, MySQL, MVC

### **EDUCATION**

**UC Irvine** - Certificate in Full Stack Development (Bootcamp)

AUGUST 2021 - OCTOBER 2021

**Udemy** - Certificate in ES6 Javascript

MAY 2021

San Diego Community College - Certificate in C++ Programming

AUGUST 2020

**Liberty University** - BS, Interdisciplinary Studies (Business & Philosophy)

2008 - 2013

### **PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS**

#### Jofer

Repo: <a href="https://github.com/sequint/Jofer">https://github.com/sequint/Jofer</a> | Deploy: <a href="https://jofer.herokuapp.com">https://jofer.herokuapp.com</a>

- **Summary:** An app that allows employers to easily communicate with applicants throughout an application process and better communicate declines.
- Role: React Engineer / Team Lead
- **Responsibilities:** Developed back end and react components while leading a team of six developers over two weeks with daily sprint activities culminating in a final project.
- **Technologies:** React.js, Javascript, React Beautiful DND, Avatar UI, React-bootstrap, Node.js, MongoDB, Express.js, Passport.js

#### **PUB**

Repo: <a href="https://github.com/sequint/pub">https://github.com/sequint/pub</a> | Deploy: <a href="https://pure-brook-86019.herokuapp.com/">https://pure-brook-86019.herokuapp.com/</a>

- **Summary:** An app that allows users to create and manage projects that they are working on, while tracking other projects that they like.
- Role: Back-End Engineer / Front End JS Engineer / Team Lead
- **Responsibilities:** Lead a team of four developers with daily sprint activities culminating in a full stack application, as well as developing the full backend architecture.
- Technologies: Node, Predictionary, is, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Passport, is Javascript

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Wells Fargo, San Diego** - Commercial Relationship Manager

JUNE 2018 - JULY 2021

- Managed a portfolio of commercial banking clients, tasked with growing client's businesses, and managing risk by analyzing our client's financials on a quarterly basis.
- Managed a cross-functional team to accomplish sales and risk analysis goals.
- Accomplishments: Developed a streamline way of underwriting credit by creating a
  workflow tool using Excel/VBA to better manage the credit process in a cross-functional
  team setting.

## **Wells Fargo, San Diego** - Sr. Business Banking Specialist

NOVEMBER 2014 - MAY 2018

- Managed and grew a book of 250 small business clients within the community bank.
- Maintained relationships with clients at CEO/CFO levels and handled all customer requests/complaints while managing risk for customers.
- **Accomplishments:** Maintained top performer in San Diego for three consecutive quarters and successfully pitched an idea to create an e-sig process to the companies internal idea board, which was a catalyst to the company implementing DocuSign features.